<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificialintelligence - project - Asaraog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/projects/artificialintelligence/</link>
    <description>Artificialintelligence - project | Asaraog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:09:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/projects/artificialintelligence/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
  <title>Computer Vision in Python/Go</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Computer_Vision/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Computer_Vision/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/vision.png" alt="Computer Vision in Python/Go" title="Computer Vision in Python/Go" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Image classification using neural networks with Python MNIST dataset This project utilizes the The Modified National Institute of Standards and Technology (MNIST) dataset which comprises of 60 thousand training observations and 10 thousand test observations of handwritten digits.
Due to the complexity of imaging data, connectionist network models or neural networks have been gaining significant interest in recent years. Python machine learning packages sklearn and keras have been especially useful for specifying neural network architectures.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Natural Language Processing</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/NLP/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/NLP/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/nlp.png" alt="Natural Language Processing" title="Natural Language Processing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Deep Learning Classification Models with AG News The growth of online news has led to a large volume of digital data. Natural language processing can help leverage this data for useful applications such as topic classification. Deep learning classification models are an attractive option to be used in these applications as the many layers in deep networks allow for hierarchal processing of the data (Glassner, 2021). The field of natural language processing has seen rapid growth since the advent of deep learning models with recurrent neural networks leading the charge (Ketkar &amp; Moolayil, 2021).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Healthcare-based datasets</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Health/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Health/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/health.png" alt="Healthcare-based datasets" title="Healthcare-based datasets" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Prediction of Bodyfat using a Linear Regression Model and Body Measurements Abstract
Bodyfat percentage is an important estimator for health. The most accurate method for measuring bodyfat is by underwater weighing which is time-intensive. Predictive analytics (linear regression) using indirect measurements offer a faster method to compute bodyfat percentage. This study analyzes bodyfat data determined by underwater weighing with their corresponding indirect measurements. To predict the bodyfat using these measurements, we compare a traditional linear model, regularized model, subset models (indicator, dichotomous, piecewise, polynomial), and feature engineering models (principal components analysis).]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
