<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>All Posts - Asaraog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>All Posts | Asaraog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:09:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
  <title>Neural Decoding of Smell</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Neural_Decoding/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Neural_Decoding/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/decoding3.png" alt="Neural Decoding of Smell" title="Neural Decoding of Smell" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Neural Decoding of Smell with Generative AI Masters of Science in Data Science Thesis Proposal
School of Professional Studies, Northwestern University
Abstract
Olfaction (sense of smell) and related structural abnormalities in the olfactory bulbs are among the first observed symptoms corelated with Alzhiemer’s disease (Esiri and Wilcock 1984; Thomann et al. 2009). The functional relationship between olfaction and the olfactory bulbs is poorly understood (Weiss et al. 2020). In the area of visual decoding, advances in machine learning using generative adversarial networks (GANs) have provided an unprecedented insight into neural decoding or the mapping of an individual brain’s responses and performance (Seeliger et al.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Comparing Go to Python/R</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/PythonRGo/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/PythonRGo/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/comparing.png" alt="Comparing Go to Python/R" title="Comparing Go to Python/R" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Image credit: R logo, Gopher Evaluating Go Unlike Python/R, Go is a compiled language that is more verbose but is said to run faster. For example, Uber, Amex and KhanAcademy find benefits with Go.
To benchmark Go&rsquo;s performance and runtime against Python and/or R, here are various cases:
Performing least squares regression of the Anscombe Quartet (1973) Computing summary statistics of the California Housing Prices (Miller 2015) Web crawling and scraping of Wikipedia Identifying anomalies in the MNIST dataset Least squares regression with Python and R The Go implementation is benchmarked for runtime with a previous implementation by Miller (2015) in Python/R as a reference.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Building this website in Hugo</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Website/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Website/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/hugo-preview.png" alt="Building this website in Hugo" title="Building this website in Hugo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Partial image credit Why Go? Static site generators such as Hugo were developed recently using Go. Go is a compiled language designed for today&rsquo;s multi-processor, scalable, high-performance systems. Other platforms have inherited dependency chains that can lead to infeasible build times. Realizing these benefits, Cloudfare recently migrated from Gatsby (a web framework based on JavaScript).
Demo website I first created a demo website using the Hugo Winston theme. This theme does have a Live Demo which made it simple to deploy onto Netlify.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Computer Vision in Python/Go</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Computer_Vision/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Computer_Vision/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/vision.png" alt="Computer Vision in Python/Go" title="Computer Vision in Python/Go" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Image classification using neural networks with Python MNIST dataset This project utilizes the The Modified National Institute of Standards and Technology (MNIST) dataset which comprises of 60 thousand training observations and 10 thousand test observations of handwritten digits.
Due to the complexity of imaging data, connectionist network models or neural networks have been gaining significant interest in recent years. Python machine learning packages sklearn and keras have been especially useful for specifying neural network architectures.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Front-end development in Go</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Front-end_Applications/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Front-end_Applications/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/frontend.png" alt="Front-end development in Go" title="Front-end development in Go" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>What? In the world of web and desktop applications, frameworks for different software languages such as Rails for Ruby and Electron for JavaScript are popular. Analogous to Rails, Go uses the Wails framework and offers the benefits of Go&rsquo;s reported processing speed. Wails also uses the native rendering engine unlike Electron which uses an embedded browser. Furthermore, Wails integrates user interface (UI) frameworks such as React, Vue and Svelte.
To demo Go&rsquo;s frontend capabilities, two projects are implemented here using Wails and Svelte:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Concurrency with Go</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Goroutines/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Goroutines/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/concurrent.png" alt="Concurrency with Go" title="Concurrency with Go" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>What? Concurrency or concurrent processing is breaking up a single process into independent components to coordinate compute. It is based on the idea of CSP or Communicating Sequential Processes (Brookes, Hoare, and Roscoe 1984). In contrast to parallel processing, the paradigm here is shifted towards communication and splitting of independent processes instead of sharing memory. To communicate between different processes, Go utilizes goroutines, which are similar to channels as described in CSP.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SARS‑CoV‑2 epidemiology</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/COVID/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/COVID/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/covid19.png" alt="SARS‑CoV‑2 epidemiology" title="SARS‑CoV‑2 epidemiology" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Epidemiology with agent-based models Abstract
This project aims to present a computational simulation of disease transmission using agent based modeling techniques implemented in Python using the Mesa package. By developing a custom disease model, we investigate the effects of various factors such as infection rates, recovery types, age and vaccination availability on the dynamics of an infectious disease. The findings from our simulation aim to contribute to the broader understanding of disease transmission dynamics, which has been a major focus in various fields over the last several years.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Natural Language Processing</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/NLP/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/NLP/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/nlp.png" alt="Natural Language Processing" title="Natural Language Processing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Deep Learning Classification Models with AG News The growth of online news has led to a large volume of digital data. Natural language processing can help leverage this data for useful applications such as topic classification. Deep learning classification models are an attractive option to be used in these applications as the many layers in deep networks allow for hierarchal processing of the data (Glassner, 2021). The field of natural language processing has seen rapid growth since the advent of deep learning models with recurrent neural networks leading the charge (Ketkar &amp; Moolayil, 2021).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Healthcare-based datasets</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Health/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Health/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/health.png" alt="Healthcare-based datasets" title="Healthcare-based datasets" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Prediction of Bodyfat using a Linear Regression Model and Body Measurements Abstract
Bodyfat percentage is an important estimator for health. The most accurate method for measuring bodyfat is by underwater weighing which is time-intensive. Predictive analytics (linear regression) using indirect measurements offer a faster method to compute bodyfat percentage. This study analyzes bodyfat data determined by underwater weighing with their corresponding indirect measurements. To predict the bodyfat using these measurements, we compare a traditional linear model, regularized model, subset models (indicator, dichotomous, piecewise, polynomial), and feature engineering models (principal components analysis).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Predicting Autism from MRI</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/ABIDE/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/ABIDE/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/abide.png" alt="Predicting Autism from MRI" title="Predicting Autism from MRI" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Predicting the Diagnosis of Autism using Classification Models based on fMRI Abstract
Autism spectrum disorder is a lifelong neurodevelopmental disorder that is diagnosed based on behavioral and social interaction patterns. Predictive algorithms provide a novel approach in identifying key neurological biomarkers and subsequent psychiatric diagnosis using functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) data. This study analyzes a dataset collected from studies at 17 international locations as part of the Autism Brain Imaging Dataset Exchange (ABIDE).]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
