<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>All Posts - Asaraog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>All Posts | Asaraog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
  <title>Comparing Golang with Python/R</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/PythonRGo/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/PythonRGo/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/comparing.png" alt="Comparing Golang with Python/R" title="Comparing Golang with Python/R" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Image credit: R logo, Gopher Evaluating Golang Unlike Python/R, Golang is a compiled language that is more verbose but is said to run faster. For example, Uber, Amex and KhanAcademy find benefits with Golang.
To benchmark Golang&rsquo;s performance and runtime against Python and/or R, here are various cases:
Performing least squares regression of the Anscombe Quartet (1973) Computing summary statistics of the California Housing Prices (Miller 2015) Web crawling and scraping of Wikipedia Identifying anomalies in the MNIST dataset Least squares regression with Python and R See my Github repository for further details.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Comparing Golang with Python/R</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Week2/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Week2/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/comparing.png" alt="Comparing Golang with Python/R" title="Comparing Golang with Python/R" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Image credit: R logo, Gopher Evaluating Go Golang is a compiled language that is more verbose but is said to run faster compared to R/Python. Here, Golang&rsquo;s performance and runtime is benchmarked against Python and/or R with various cases:
Performing least squares regression of the Anscombe Quartet (1973) Computing summary statistics of the California Housing Prices (Miller 2015) Web crawling and scraping of Wikipedia Identify anomalies in the MNIST dataset Least squares regression with Python and R See my Github repository for further details.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>My First Post3</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/first_post3/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 20:14:22 &#43;0800</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/first_post3/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[A blog (a truncation of &ldquo;weblog&rdquo;) is an informational website published on the World Wide Web consisting of discrete, often informal diary-style text entries (posts). Posts are typically displayed in reverse chronological order so that the most recent post appears first, at the top of the web page. Until 2009, blogs were usually the work of a single individual,[citation needed] occasionally of a small group, and often covered a single subject or topic.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Building this website with Hugo</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Website/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Website/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/hugo-preview.png" alt="Building this website with Hugo" title="Building this website with Hugo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Partial image credit Why Golang? Static site generators such as Hugo were developed recently using Golang. Golang is a compiled language designed for today&rsquo;s multi-processor, scalable, high-performance systems. Other platforms have inherited dependency chains that can lead to infeasible build times. Realizing these benefits, Cloudfare recently migrated from Gatsby (a web framework based on JavaScript).
Demo website See my Github repository for further details.
I first created a demo website using the Hugo Winston theme.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Building this website with Hugo</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Week3/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Week3/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/hugo-preview.png" alt="Building this website with Hugo" title="Building this website with Hugo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Partial image credit Why? Golang is a compiled language designed for today&rsquo;s multi-processor, scalable, high-performance systems. Known for concurrent data processing, Uber uses Golang on the backend. Static site generators such as Hugo were developed recently using Golang. Other platforms have inherited dependency chains that can lead to infeasible build times. For example, Cloudfare recently migrated from Gatsby.
Demo website See my Github repository for further details.
I first created a demo website using the Hugo Winston theme.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Concurrency with Golang</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Goroutines/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Goroutines/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/concurrent.png" alt="Concurrency with Golang" title="Concurrency with Golang" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>What? Concurrency or concurrent processing is breaking up a single process into independent components to coordinate compute. It is based on the idea of CSP or Communicating Sequential Processes (Brookes, Hoare, and Roscoe 1984). In contrast to parallel processing, the paradigm here is shifted towards communication and splitting of independent processes instead of sharing memory. To communicate between different processes, Golang utilizes goroutines, which are similar to channels as described in CSP.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Concurrency with Golang</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Week6/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Week6/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/concurrent.png" alt="Concurrency with Golang" title="Concurrency with Golang" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>What? Concurrency is breaking up a single process into independent components and then making a plan on how they will compute. It is based on the idea of CSP or Communicating Sequential Processes (Brookes, Hoare, and Roscoe 1984). The paradigm here is shifted towards communication and splitting of independent processes instead of sharing memory in parallel processing. To communicate between different processes, Golang utilizes goroutines, which are similar to channels as described in CSP.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Front-end development with Golang</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Week8/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Week8/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/frontend.png" alt="Front-end development with Golang" title="Front-end development with Golang" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>What? Analogous to Rails for Ruby, Golang has Wails for front-end application development. Popular front-end frameworks for JavaScript such as React, Angular and Vue can be used with Wails. Built on Golang, Wails uses the native rendering engine rather than an embedded browser (https://www.electronjs.org/)
Svelte is a lighter and beginner-friendly front-end framework. Wails and Svelte are used for two projects:
Assisted Writing Application Chatbot To install Wails onto your machine:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Front-end software development using Golang</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/Front-end_Applications/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/Front-end_Applications/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/frontend.png" alt="Front-end software development using Golang" title="Front-end software development using Golang" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>What? In the world of web and desktop applications, frameworks for different software languages such as Rails for Ruby and Electron for JavaScript are popular. Analogous to Rails, Golang uses the Wails framework and offers the benefits of Golang&rsquo;s reported processing speed. Wails also uses the native rendering engine unlike Electron which uses an embedded browser. Furthermore, Wails integrates user interface (UI) frameworks such as React, Vue and Svelte.
To demo Golang&rsquo;s frontend capabilities, two projects are implemented here using Wails and Svelte:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MNIST Dataset</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/MNIST/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>Author</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/MNIST/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/mnnist.png" alt="MNIST Dataset" title="MNIST Dataset" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>MNIST Dataset This project utilizes the The Modified National Institute of Standards and Technology (MNIST) dataset which comprises of 60 thousand training observations and 10 thousand test observations of handwritten digits.
Image classification using neural networks with Python See my report for further details.
Due to the complexity of imaging data, connectionist network models or neural networks have been gaining significant interest in recent years. This study uses various single hidden layer neural network models (single node, double node, many nodes), preprocessing inputs using principal component analysis (PCA) or ranked inputs from a random forest analysis.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
