<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>गोलांग - डेटा विज्ञान - असरावग</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/hi/datascience/%E0%A4%97%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%97/</link>
    <description>गोलांग - डेटा विज्ञान | असरावग</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>hi</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/hi/datascience/%E0%A4%97%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%82%E0%A4%97/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
  <title>Comparing Golang with Python/R</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/hi/Week2/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>रचयिता</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/hi/Week2/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/comparing.png" alt="Comparing Golang with Python/R" title="Comparing Golang with Python/R" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Image credit: R logo, Gopher Evaluating Go Golang is a compiled language that is more verbose but is said to run faster compared to R/Python. Here, Golang&rsquo;s performance and runtime is benchmarked against Python and/or R with various cases:
Performing least squares regression of the Anscombe Quartet (1973) Computing summary statistics of the California Housing Prices (Miller 2015) Web crawling and scraping of Wikipedia Identify anomalies in the MNIST dataset Least squares regression with Python and R See Github repository for further details.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Building this website with Hugo</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/hi/Week3/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>रचयिता</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/hi/Week3/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/hugo-preview.png" alt="Building this website with Hugo" title="Building this website with Hugo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Partial image credit Why? Golang is a compiled language designed for today&rsquo;s multi-processor, scalable, high-performance systems. Known for concurrent data processing, Uber uses Golang on the backend. Static site generators such as Hugo were developed recently using Golang. Other platforms have inherited dependency chains that can lead to infeasible build times. For example, Cloudfare recently migrated from Gatsby.
Demo I first created a demo website using the Hugo Winston theme.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Concurrency with Golang</title>
  <link>//localhost:1313/hi/Week6/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <author>रचयिता</author>
  <guid>//localhost:1313/hi/Week6/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image"><img loading="eager" src="/images/concurrent.png" alt="Concurrency with Golang" title="Concurrency with Golang" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"/></div>Image credit: R logo, Gopher What? Concurrency is breaking up a single process into independent components and then making a plan on how they will compute. It is based on the idea of CSP or Communicating Sequential Processes (Brookes, Hoare, and Roscoe 1984). The paradigm here is shifted towards communication and splitting of independent processes instead of sharing memory in parallel processing. To communicate between different processes, Golang utilizes goroutines, which are similar to channels as described in CSP.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
